# **Benjamin Corbett**

Full-Stack Software Developer

(609) 320-7586 · crystaledgedev22@gmail.com

LinkedIn • GitHub • Portfolio

# **Summary**

I am a Full-Stack Software Developer who specializes in creating user-friendly applications using React with Next.js or Vite. I have experience using Redux for state management and developing scalable back-end systems with Express.js, Node.js, and MongoDB. I have implemented WebSockets for real-time communication and conducted unit-tests with Jest. When styling my applications I use Material UI, Tailwind CSS, or Bootstrap and have worked on a team using Git-workflow and Agile methodologies.

Outside of tech, I enjoy practicing yoga, cooking, projects around the house, surfing, hiking, and spending time with my wife and australian shepherd. My current interests are learning how to work with **TypeScript** and **Amazon Web Services (AWS).** 

#### **Tech Stack**

React • Redux • Next.js • Redux Toolkit • MongoDB • Node.js • Express.js • Websockets • JavaScript • RESTful API • Jest • Bootstrap • Tailwind CSS • Material UI

# **Projects**

# SolarRise <u>Repository</u> | <u>Demo</u>

React | Vite | Google Maps API | AWS S3 | Tailwind CSS

- Worked on a team of 9 other participants in an **Agile environment** to develop SolarRise, an application that enables Los Angeles residents to request appointments for solar panel evaluation and installation.
- Used **Google Maps API** to implement an autocomplete feature for the resident to enter their address along with their personal information and then used **Axios** to handle a GET request to have the address validated against an address database stored in an **Amazon S3 Bucket**.
- Used Discord to communicate with the team and conduct **Sprint Reviews**, **Sprint Retrospectives**, **Sprint Planning**, and **Daily Standups** for the duration of the project.
- Admins are able to securely login in to view, delete, or approve requested appointments and then select appointments that they want to visit.
- By using **React PDF** and **Google Maps API**, Admins are able to map out their route or export their appointments in PDF format.
- Adhered to Git-workflow best practices and conducted code reviews each time we completed an assigned task.

# Weather Station Repository | Demo

React | Next.js | Redux Toolkit | Bootstrap | OpenWeather API | Material UI

• Built a responsive 5-day weather forecast application, leveraging **React** and **Next.js** to provide a seamless user experience.

- Integrated the **OpenWeather API** to dynamically fetch real-time temperature, pressure, and humidity data for any city.
- Designed a custom auto-complete input field using **Google Places API**, enabling users to see relevant search results based on their input
- Implemented Redux Toolkit for efficient state management and handling of asynchronous API requests.

#### Contact List v2 Repository | Demo

#### React | Next.js | Bootstrap

- Constructed a modern rolodex application that enables users to add, delete, and view contact profiles from a pre-generated JSON database.
- Utilized React's Context API to efficiently manage state and share functions across multiple components.
- Implemented **PropTypes** to ensure strict and accurate prop validation for all components.
- Included **Next.js** features such as **CSS Modules** and **Next.js routing** for seamless navigation between pages.

#### **Education**

#### Parsity February 2022 - June 2022

• Completed an intensive online full-stack software engineering program focused on **MongoDB**, **Express.js**, **React**, **Node.js** and industry best practices in software development.

# **Experience**

# Software Developer - Chingu November 2024 - present

- Voyages with Chingu are workplace simulations that are broken into 6 sprints where I work with a team to design, build, and deploy an assigned web application.
- Leverage **Jira** for task management and sprint planning while adhering to **Agile** methodologies through **daily standups**, **sprint reviews**, and **retrospectives**.
- Worked together to strengthen each other's technical and teamwork skills by actively contributing to app development, conducting peer code reviews, and deploying production-ready code.
- Developed **SolarRise**, a platform for LA residents to request a solar evaluation and for admins to login to view and plan requested appointments.

### Commercial Fisherman June 2011-August 2024

My time working in this position helped me develop strong leadership qualities and to **quickly adapt** to **changing environments.** This role taught me the importance of a strong **team mentality**, **good attitude** on the job, and **responsibility**.

- An average trip lasts about 10 days in an effort to sustainably harvest scallops, squid, flounder, or sea bass.
- · Certified safety drill instructor.
- · CPR/First Aid certified.